Register of the Burnett Bolloten Papers, 1923-1991
Hoover Institution Archives
- CLIPPINGS, 1934-1976. (Box 15-82)
  - General
    - Chronological. NOTE: Most of this material reflects a prior chronological arrangement which includes many of the same publications itemized subsequently
      - 1937 September 17-October 9 (Box 44, Folder 1-12)
      - 1937 October 10-29 (Box 45, Folder 1-10)
      - 1937 October 30-November 30 (Box 46, Folder 1-16)
      - 1937 December 1-31 (Box 47, Folder 1-15)
      - 1938 January 1-February 10 (Box 48, Folder 1-20)
      - 1938 February 11-March 31 (Box 49, Folder 1-24)
      - 1938 April 1-24 (Box 50, Folder 1-12)
      - 1938 April 25-May 31 (Box 51, Folder 1-18)
      - 1938 June 1-28 (Box 52, Folder 1-14)
      - 1938 June 29-July 31 (Box 53, Folder 1-16)
      - 1938 August 1-September 2 (Box 54, Folder 1-16)
      - 1938 September 3-October 12 (Box 55, Folder 1-20)
      - 1938 October 13-November 10 (Box 56, Folder 1-14)
      - 1938 November 11-December 10 (Box 57, Folder 1-15)
      - 1938 December 11-1939 January 6 (Box 58, Folder 1-13)
      - 1939 January 7-26 (Box 59, Folder 1-10)
      - 1939 January 27-February 8 (Box 60, Folder 1-7)
      - 1939 February 9-19 (Box 61, Folder 1-7)
      - 1939 February 20-March 6 (Box 62, Folder 1-7)
      - 1939 March 7-18 (Box 63, Folder 1-6)
      - 1939 March 19-April 14 (Box 64, Folder 1-13)
      - 1939 April 15-June 15 (Box 65, Folder 1-13)
      - 1939 June 16-November 30 (Box 66, Folder 1-11)
      - 1939 December-1940 May (Box 67, Folder 1-8)
      - 1940 June-1941 December (Box 68, Folder 1-10)
      - 1942 January-1943 June (Box 69, Folder 1-9)
      - 1943 July-1946 December (Box 70, Folder 1-10)
  - Acracia, 1937 April-1938 February (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Adelante, 1934 January-1937 October (Folder 2)
  - Anarquia, 1937 July (Folder 3)
  - Avant, 1936 July (Folder 4)
  - La Batalla
    - 1934 May-1936 December (Folder 5-8)
    - 1937 January-1976 March (Box 72, Folder 1-4)
  - C.N.T.
    - 1936 June-1937 April (Folder 5-6)
    - 1937 May-1939 March (Box 73, Folder 1-5)
  - Castilla Libre, 1936 March-1939 March (Folder 6-7)
  - Claridad, 1937 February-1939 March (Box 74, Folder 1-2)
  - El Combatiente Rojo, 1936 September-1937 September (Folder 3)
  - La Correspondencia [de Valencia], 1936 October-1937 October (Folder 4-5)
  - Cultura y Accion, 1937 April-August (Folder 6)
  - El Dia Grafico
    - 1936 July-December (Folder 7)
    - 1937 January-1939 January (Box 75, Folder 1-3)
  - Fragua Social
    - 1937 January-December (Folder 4-7)
    - 1938 January-1939 March (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Frente Libertario, 1936 December-1939 March (Folder 2-5)
  - Frente Rojo
    - 1937 January-May (Folder 6)
    - 1937 June-1939 February (Box 77, Folder 1-7)
  - La Humanitat, 1936 July-1938 July (Folder 8)
  - Ideas, 1937 July-August (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Mundo Obrero, 1936 April-1939 March (Folder 2-3)
  - Nosotros, 1937 February-November (Folder 4)
  - Las Noticias, 1936 July-1938 December (Folder 5)
  - Politica, 1936 May-1939 March (Folder 6-7)
  - La Publicitat, 1936 May-1938 December (Folder 8)
  - Ruta, 1936 November-1937 June (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - El Socialista, 1936 July-1939 March (Folder 2-4)
  - Solidaridad Obrera
    - 1936 January-1937 March (Folder 5-7)
    - 1937 April-1938 October (Box 80, Folder 1-6)
    - 1938 November-December (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Tierra y Libertad, 1933 November-1938 December (Folder 2-4)
  - Treball
    - 1936 January-1937 December (Folder 5-8)
    - 1938 October-December (Box 82, Folder 1-2)
  - Ultima Hora, 1936 August-1937 October (Folder 3)
  - La Vanguardia, 1936 July-1939 March (Folder 4-6)
  - Verdad, 1936 January-1939 August (Folder 7)
- SPANISH CIVIL WAR SUBJECT FILE, 1931-1987 (Box 83-102)
  Correspondence, reports, printed articles, printed excerpts, clippings, pamphlets, flyers, speeches, bulletins, newsletters, resolutions, conference proceedings, circulars, transcripts, notes, statutes and by-laws, bibliographies, biographical material, interview notes, lists, maps, and bound volumes of miscellaneous documents. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - General
    - General. Bound volumes of miscellaneous documents, SEE: Appendix A for itemized list, 1936-1945. (Box 83, Folder 1-4)
    - Biographical material and obituaries, Arranged alphabetically, 1935-1982. (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Interview notes, 1936-1965 (Folder 2)
    - Lists and indices (Folder 3)
    - Maps, n.d (Folder 4)
    - Reports, Photocopies of material in the Rudolf Rocker Collection, International Institute of Social History, Amsterdam. SEE: Appendix B for itemized list, 1936-1939. (Folder 5-7)
    - Reports (Box 85, Folder 1-3)
  - Agrarian issues. Includes material relating to agrarian collectives and the Unio de Rabassaires. Printed articles and excerpts, clippings, letters, report, by-laws, and typescript copies of Edward Malefakis, "The Agrarian Problem and the Republic," and Miguel Vidal, "El Campo Espaiol,", 1936-1986 (Folder 4-7)
  - Alicante (Province)
    - General. Conference proceedings, clippings, printed excerpts, and bulletins, 1937-1972 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Collectives
      - General. Letters relating to the periodical Liberacion, 1937-1939 (Folder 2)
      - Consejo Obrero de Industrias Metalurgicas Socializadas. Letters and reports, 1936-1937 (Folder 3)
      - Consejo Obrero de la Industria de Calzado y Similares. Letters and reports, 1938-1939 (Folder 4)
    - Partido Comunista de Espaia. Reports and correspondence between local and provincial committees, 1936-1938 (Folder 5)
  - Almeria incident, Pamphlet, and printed article and excerpts, ca. 1937-1977, 1937 May. (Folder 6)
  - Amigos de Durruti. Pamphlet, flyers, clippings, printed excerpts, notes, chronology, and a typescript copy of "Historia de la 'Agrupacion Amigos de Durruti," (incomplete) SEE ALSO: CORRESPONDENCE FILE/Balius, Jaime, 1937-1984. (Folder 7)
  - Andrade Rodriguez, Juan. Typescript copy of George Esenwein, "Juan Andrade Rodriguez " n.d., (1897-1982) (Folder 8)
  - Antecedents
    - General. Includes material related to the Falange Espaiola and to the death of Jose Calvo Sotelo. Printed excerpts and printed articles by Diego Abad de Santillan, Lawrence A. Fernsworth and others, 1936-1982 (Folder 9)
    - Asturias, 1934 uprising. Clippings and printed articles by Harry Gannes and another, 1935-1985 (Folder 10)
  - Antonov-Ovseenko, Vladimir. Biographical sketch, notes, and printed articles by Jaume Miravitlles and another, 1956-1982 (Folder 11)
  - Aragon. Clippings, printed excerpts, notes, typescript meeting transcript, and a typescript copy of Jose Duque, "La Situacion de Aragon al Comienzo de la Guerra," SEE ALSO: Military organization and operations, 1936-1983. (Box 87, Folder 1-2)
  - Azaia, Manuel. Speeches and writings by Azaia, printed articles and excerpts, notes, and clippings, 1932-1984 (Folder 3-4)
  - Barcelona, Events of SEE ALSO: CLIPPINGS/ General/Chronological/1937 May
    - Non-printed matter. Notes, statement, transcripts of communications between Manuel Azaia and Indalecio Prieto, and reports by Jaime Aiguade, Jordi Arquer, Luis Companys, Hugo Oehler, David Wingate Pike and others
      - Undated (Folder 6-7)
      - 1937-1983 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Printed matter. Clippings, and printed articles and excerpts by Claude Bowers, H. N. Brailsford, Lawrence Fernsworth, Agustin Souchy, Bertram Wolfe and others, 1937-1982 (Folder 2-4)
  - Bergamin, Jose. Clippings, 1936-ca. 1982 (Folder 5)
  - Berneri, Camillo. Printed writings by Berneri, clippings, and printed articles by Giovanna Berneri, Maria Luisa Berneri, Max Soutin and others, 1936-1980 (Folder 6)
  - Besteiro, Julian. Clippings, letter, notes, and printed articles and excerpts by F. Ferrandiz Alborz, Jesus Hernandez, Salvador de Madariaga, Gabriel Moron and others, SEE ALSO: Final events, 1939 March, 1939-1986. (Folder 7)
  - Casares Quiroga, Santiago. Typescript biography by Alfonso Quintana y Peia, 1982 (Folder 8)
  - Catalonia. Primarily relates to politics and government. Statutes, clippings, printed articles and excerpts by Manuel Benavides, Allison Peers, Angel Ossorio, Carles Pi Sunyer and others, untitled typescript by Ricardo del Rio relating to the last days of the war in Catalonia, and a typescript copy of Gabriel Jackson, "Autonomous Catalonia and the Spanish Republic" (Folder 9)
    - Undated (Folder 10)
    - 1931-1980 (Box 89, Folder 1-2)
  - Collectivization. SEE ALSO: Agrarian issues
    - Non-printed matter. Circulars, bulletins, notes, and typescript copies of "Work and Revolution: Workers' Control in Barcelona in the Spanish Civil War, " John Amsden, "Industrial Collectivisation Under Workers' Control: Catalonia, 1936-1939," and Miguel Jimenez, "Problemas de la Revolucion Espaiola," and a mimeograph copy of Gabriel Jackson, "The Living Experience of the Spanish Civil War Collectives," 1936-1969, 1936-1938 (Folder 3)
    - Printed matter. By-laws, clippings, and printed articles and excerpts by Gaston Leval, J. Oltra Pico, Jacinto Toryho and others, 1936-1979 (Folder 4-5)
  - Comite Central de Milicias Antifascistas de Catalunya. Clippings, printed excerpts by Juan Garcia Oliver, Josep Tarradellas, Jacinto Toryho and others, statement by Buenaventura Durruti, and a typescript copy of George Esenwein, "Central Antifascist Militias Committee,", 1936-1972 (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Communist International (Comintern). Clippings, letter, biographical sketches, printed articles by Benjamin Gitlow, Arthur Koestler, J. Martinez Amutio and others, and a typescript memoir by Herbert Matthews, SEE ALSO: Soviet Union, 1934-1980. (Folder 2)
  - Companys, Luis. Speeches by Companys and Indalecio Prieto, clippings, and printed excerpts and articles by Diego Abad de Santillan, Angel Ossorio and others, 1933-1971 (Folder 3)
  - Confederacion Nacional del Trabajo (CNT)-Federacion Anarquista Iberica (FAI). SEE ALSO: Federacion Anarquista Iberica (FAI)
    - Non-printed matter
      - General. Archival guide to material in the International Institute of Social History, bulletin, press reports, and a typescript copy of George Esenwein, "Anarchism During the Second Republic: The Emergence of a Mass Movement,", 1937-1981 (Folder 4-5)
    - Boletin de Informacion
      - 1936 August-December (Folder 6)
      - 1937 January-1938 April (Box 91, Folder 1-3)
    - Printed matter. Clippings, circular, by-laws, conference proceedings, reports, and printed excerpts and articles by Jose Garcia Pradas, Jacinto Toryho and others, 1931-1986 (Folder 4-7)
  - Consejo Economico Confederal. Circulars, reports, chart, and clippings, ca. 1937-1938 (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Constitution. Printed excerpts and printed copy of the Spanish constitution (Folder 2)
  - Cortada, Roldan, Assassination of. Clippings, 1937 (Folder 3)
  - Durruti, Buenaventura. Speech by Durruti, clippings, notes, and printed excerpts and articles by Diego Abad de Santillan, Emma Goldman and others, SEE ALSO: MICROFILM/Reel 259, 1936-1978. (Folder 4)
  - Economics and finance. Speech by Mariano Cardona Rossell, clippings, reports, notes, and printed excerpts, 1936-1977 (Folder 5)
  - Espionage and sabotage. Telegram and printed articles, 1938-1978 (Folder 6)
  - Euzkadi (Spain). Relates to Basque nationalism and the war in the north. Clippings, printed excerpts and articles, pamphlet by Manuel Chiapuso, Generalidades sobre Euzkadi y la C.N.T., typescript report by Jose Antonio Aguirre, and a typescript copy of Manuel de Irujo, "La Guerra Civil en Euzkadi antes del Estatuto," SEE ALSO: SUBJECT FILE/Euzkadi, 1936-1986. (Folder 7)
  - Federacion Anarquista Iberica (FAI). Printed interview, excerpts, and articles, conference report, speech, and notes, 1937-1977 (Folder 8)
  - Final events, Includes material relating to the Casado coup and the conspiracy at the Cartagena naval base, 1939 March.
    - Non-printed matter. Bulletins, letters by Jose Estrugo, Juan Negrin and Ramon Lamoneda, and typescript and mimeograph reports, including F. Ferrandiz Alborz, "Llego la Bestia,", 1937-1987 (Folder 8)
    - Printed matter. Speeches by Julian Besteiro and Segismundo Casado, printed articles and excerpts by Pedro Checa, Lawrence Fernsworth, Ignacio Hidalgo de Cisneros, Herbert Matthews, Jose Garcia Pradas, Georges Soria, Cipriano de Rivas Cherif and others, 1939-1983 (Box 93, Folder 1-2)
  - Foreign relations and foreign public opinion. SEE ALSO: SUBJECT FILE/World politics, 1933-1945
    - General. Telegrams, printed articles and excerpts, typescript copy of Sally V. McBean, "Spain's Courtship of the West," and mimeograph copies of John Jagger and Wilfrid Roberts, "The Anglo-Italian Agreement and 'Settlement' in Spain," and Rudolf de Jong, "The Netherlands and the Spanish Civil War,", 1937-1980 (Folder 3)
    - France. Printed articles and excerpts, telegram, clipping, and printed diplomatic correspondence, 1937-1981 (Folder 4)
    - Germany. Printed articles and excerpts, printed copies and photocopies of diplomatic correspondence and other documents, letter, and clippings, 1936-1980 (Folder 5)
    - Great Britain. Printed articles and excerpts, telegram, and photocopies of British Cabinet documents, 1936-1985 (Folder 6)
    - Italy. Printed article, bibliography, and printed copies of diplomatic documents, 1936-1982 (Folder 7)
    - Latin America. Telegrams, typescript book review, and printed article and excerpts, 1939-1985 (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - United States. Printed articles and excerpts, telegram, newsletters, and printed diplomatic correspondence, 1939-1982 (Folder 2)
  - Fourth International. Bulletins, clippings ( La Voz Leninista), circular, and reports, including a report by Manuel Grandizo Munis to Leon Trotsky, SEE ALSO: Trotsky, Leon, 1936-1947. (Folder 3)
  - Franco, Francisco. Speech by Franco, poems, clippings, and printed articles and excerpts, SEE ALSO: SUBJECT FILE/Spain (Franco regime), 1939-1967. (Folder 4)
  - Gero, Erno. Clippings and printed excerpts, SEE ALSO: Antonov-Ovseenko, Vladimir, 1950-1980. (Folder 5)
  - Giral, Francisco. Printed article, 1980 (Folder 6)
  - Gold. Primarily relates to the transfer of gold to the Soviet Union in 1936. Bulletin, correspondence with the British Museum, and printed excerpts and articles by Alexander Orlov, Angel Viias and others, 1966-1981 (Folder 7)
  - Guernica. Printed articles, excerpts, and clippings, 1937-1978 (Folder 8)
  - Hemingway, Ernest. Clippings, printed articles and excerpts, and printed writing by Hemingway, SEE ALSO: SPEECHES AND WRITINGS BY OTHERS/Marty, Andre, 1961-1982. (Folder 9)
  - History, historiography, and bibliography
    - General. Printed articles, notes, clippings, bibliography, and mimeograph copies of David W. Pike, "The Spanish Civil War: A New Perspective," and Stephen Schwartz, "The Spanish Civil War: Fifty Years After,", 1945-1987 (Folder 10-11)
    - Boletin de Orientacion Bibliografica. Serial issues, 1966-1976 (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Industry. Includes material relating to defense production. Printed excerpts and articles, clippings, circular, letters, notes, and bulletins, 1936-1978 (Folder 2)
  - International brigades. Printed articles and excerpts by Alvah Bessie, Luigi Longo (Gallo), John McNair, Gustav Regler, Carlo Rosselli and others, pamphlet, newsletters ( Volunteer for Liberty), reports, correspondence, and a mimeograph copy of Verle B. Johnston, "The International Brigades in the Spanish Civil War, " with additional comments by Johnston, 1936-1939
    - 1936-1966 (Folder 3-5)
    - 1967-1977 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Journalism and the war. Clippings, printed articles, and excerpts by Claud Cockburn, Malcolm Cowley, Martha Gellhorn, Joaquin Maurin and others, 1935-1985 (Folder 2)
  - Justice, public order, and human rights. Clippings, telegram, report, notes, and printed articles and excerpts, 1937-1981 (Folder 3)
  - Juventudes Socialistas Unificadas (JSU). Speech, conference reports, position papers, clippings (primarily Ahora), and printed excerpts, 1937-1982 (Folder 4-5)
  - Kleber, Emil. Printed excerpts, and typescript notes of interviews with Claud Cockburn, Irene Hudson and others, 1936-1961 (Folder 6)
  - Krivitsky, Walter G. Printed articles and excerpts by Krivitsky and others, poem, and a mimeograph copy of John Amsden, "Krivitsky,", 1939-1978 (Folder 7)
  - Kuznetsov, Nicolai. Notes, clippings, biographical sketch, and printed excerpt by Kuznetsov, 1974 (Folder 8)
  - Literature and the war. Includes material relating to Federico Garcia Lorca, Benjamin Peret, Miguel de Unamuno and others. Pamphlet entitled Escritores asesinados por los rojos, mimeograph bulletin, clippings, and printed excerpts and articles by Lillian Hellman, John Sommerfield and others, 1937-1987 (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - Lopez, Juan. Clippings, 1947-1972 (Folder 2)
  - Llopis, Rodolfo. Correspondence, printed article, and writing by Llopis, 1935-1971 (Folder 3)
  - Madrid, Defense of. Newletters ( Milicia Popular), clippings, and printed excerpts and articles by Enrique Lister and others, SEE ALSO: Miaja, Jose, 1936-1978. (Folder 4)
  - Malraux, Andre. Clippings, printed article, and a typescript copy of Bertram Wolfe, "The Autobiography of a Culture Hero,", 1968-1978 (Folder 5)
  - Miaja, Jose. Minutes of the Madrid Defense Junta and communications between Miaja and the central government, letter, printed articles and excerpts, shorthand interview notes, and typescript notes, 1936-1944 (Folder 6)
    - General
      - General. Biographical notes and clippings, 1937-1972 (Folder 7)
      - Non-printed matter. Letters to Carlos Contreras (Vittorio Vidali) by Santiago Alvarez, Enrique Lister, and others, interviews by Enrique Lumen, Arturo Perucho, Francisco Giner de los Rios, Pedro Martinez Carton, and Daniel Tapia, bulletins, circulars, press release, reports, notes, lists, and typescript copies of "Peripecies d'un Alferes de l'Exercit de Catalunya," Santiago Alvarez, "Experiencias del Trabajo Practico de un Comisario," Alberto F. Ballesteros, "Lo Occurido en Malaga," and Enrique Castro, "Las Tareas de los Comisarios en la Fase Actual de la Guerra,", 1937-1939 (Folder 8)
      - Printed matter. Circulars, bulletins, clippings, and printed excerpts and articles, 1936-1983 (Folder 9-11)
    - Popular militias. Includes material relating to groups which were reorganized as units in the regular army. SEE ALSO: Comite Central de Milicias Antifascistas de Catalunya
      - General. Clippings, printed excerpts, notes, and resolutions, 1936-1937 (Box 98, Folder 1)
      - Fifth Regiment. Printed excerpts and notes relating to Enrique Castro, ca. 1936-1978 (Folder 2)
      - Iron Column. Notes, printed excerpt, and newsletters ( Linea de Fuego), 1936-1976 (Folder 3)
      - Twenty-Sixth Division. Printed article, 1938 (Folder 4)
      - Twenty-Eighth Division. Clippings and official bulletins, 1938-1939 (Folder 5)
      - Twenty-Ninth Division. Clippings, 1937-1938 (Folder 6)
  - Monarchists. Printed article, 1977 (Folder 7)
  - Morocco, Spanish. Printed articles and excerpts, 1964-ca. 1979 (Folder 8)
  - NKVD (Narodnyi kommissariat vnutrennykh del). Pamphlets by Katia Landau, Le Stalinisme en Espagne, and John McGovern, Terror in Spain, printed excerpts, clippings, flyer, biographical sketch of Leonid Eitingon, and a typescript copy of Charles A. Orr, "Some Facts on the Persecution of Foreign Revolutionaries in 'Republican' Spain," SEE ALSO: Soviet Union, 1937-1976. (Folder 9)
  - Nationalists and Falangists. Clippings, printed excerpts and articles, bulletin, and a typescript copy of Luis S. Ponce de Leon, "Las Primeras Semanas de la Guerra Civil Espaiola en los Periodicos Nacionalistas,", 1936-1980 (Folder 10)
  - Navy and naval operations. Printed articles and excerpts, telegram, and notes, SEE ALSO: Final Events, 1938-1984. (Folder 11)
  - Negrin, Juan. Speeches by Negrin, notes, clippings, printed article and excerpts, 1939-1985 (Folder 12)
  - Nin, Andres. Printed excerpts and articles, clippings, pamphlet, press release, and typescript copies of Julio Antonio Maurin, "The Assassination of Andres Nin," George Esenwein, "Andreu Nin, " and Stephen Schwartz, "To the Memory of Andreu Nin," 1937-1985, 1892-1937 (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Orlov, Alexander. Letters and writings by Bertram Wolfe, report, and printed articles and excerpts by Ignacio Iglesias, Jaume Miravitlles and another, 1969-1979 (Folder 2)
  - Partido Comunista de Espaia (PCE). Speeches, printed excerpts and articles by Juan Andrade, Pedro Checa and others, clippings, circular, program statement, meeting and conference reports, notes, and a typescript copy of "Por Que y Como Salimos de Espaia los Guerrilleros y el S.I.E.P.," by Valentin Gonzalez and others, SEE ALSO: SUBJECT FILE/Partido Comunista de Espaia, 1934-1980. (Folder 3-4)
  - Partido Obrero de Unificacion Marxista (POUM)
    - Non-printed matter
      - General. Reports, position statements, telegrams sent to General Miaja protesting the dissolution of the POUM, notes, and typescript copies of Wilebaldo Solano, "Notas sobre el POUM en la Revolucion de 1936," and "La Revolucion Espaiola y el POUM,", 1937-1978 (Folder 5)
      - Independent News. Relates to the suppression of the POUM and the trials of its leaders
        - 1937 May-1938 July (Folder 6-7)
        - 1938 August-1939 January (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Printed matter. Flyer, resolutions, pamphlets, printed articles, excerpts, and clippings by Jose Bergamin, Fenner Brockway, Harry Gannes, Julian Gorkin, Mikhail Koltzov, John McNair, Victor Serge, Georges Soria and others, 1936-1972 (Folder 2-4)
  - Partido Socialista Obrero Espaiol (PSOE). Printed excerpts, clippings, and circular, SEE ALSO: SUBJECT FILE/Partido Socialista Obrero Espaiol, 1937-1973. (Folder 5)
  - Partit Socialista Unificat de Catalunya (PSUC). Conference reports, speech, printed excerpts, clippings, and notes, SEE ALSO: SUBJECT FILE/Partit Socialista Unificat de Catalunya, 1936-1979. (Folder 6)
  - Politics and government
    - Non-printed matter. Telegrams, bulletins, chart, notes, and typescript copies of "El P.C. y la Unidad Antifascista" (incomplete), and Edward Malefakis "Internal Political Problems and Loyalties: The Republican Side in the Spanish Civil War,", 1938-ca. 1970 (Folder 7)
    - Printed matter. Clippings, bulletins, minutes, serial issues, pamphlet, and printed excerpts and articles by Franz Borkenau, Claude Bowers, Lawrence Fernsworth, Louis Fischer, Jose Maria Gil Robles, John Langdon-Davies, Jesus Perez Salas, Carles Pi Sunyer and others
      - Undated (Folder 8)
      - 1936-1937 April (Box 101, Folder 1)
      - 1937 May-1981 (Folder 2-3)
  - Primo de Rivera, Jose Antonio. Clippings, printed article, and notes, 1951-1977 (Folder 4)
  - Religion. Clippings, printed excerpts and articles, serial issue, and notes, ca. 1938-1987 (Folder 5)
  - Saborit, Andres. Clippings and printed interview, 1968-1980 (Folder 6)
  - Servicio de Investigacion Militar. Includes material relating to Gustavo Duran and Jose Muioz Lopez. Notes, and printed articles and excerpts, 1937-1980 (Folder 7)
  - Soviet Union. Printed biographical sketches, notes, clippings, printed excerpts and articles, letters, printed diplomatic correspondence, a pamphlet entitled Soviet Russia and Spain, and a typescript dissertation excerpt by David E. Allen Jr., "The Soviet Union and the Spanish Civil War: " SEE ALSO: SUBJECT FILE/Soviet Union, 1936-1939.
    - 1936-1965 (Folder 8-9)
    - 1967-1986 (Box 102, Folder 1)
  - Thirteen Points. Printed excerpts and articles, 1938-1941 (Folder 2)
  - Togliatti, Palmiro. Clippings and printed excerpts, 1965-1973 (Folder 3)